{
  "data": [
    {
      "title": "Types of Blood Specimen",
      "answers": ["Venous Whole Blood", "Serum", "Plasma", "Arterial Blood"],
      "questions": [
        { "forAns": 1, "question": "For hematology, immunohematology" },
        {
          "forAns": 1,
          "question": "Only used in Chemistry for HbA1c determination"
        },
        {
          "forAns": 2,
          "question": "Chemistry and Immunology / Serology"
        },
        {
          "forAns": 3,
          "question": "For Hematology"
        },
        {
          "forAns": 3,
          "question": "Used in chemistry, only if serum is not available"
        },
        {
          "forAns": 4,
          "question": "For Chemistry"
        },
        {
          "forAns": 4,
          "question": "Used for blood gas analysis and pH measurement"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "title": "Patient Identification Procedure",
      "answers": [
        "Conscious Inpatients",
        "Sleeping patients",
        "Mentally-incompetent patients",
        "Outpatient patient"
      ],
      "questions": [
        {
          "forAns": 1,
          "question": "Verbally ask their full name and verify with the ID bracelet placed on the arm of the patient"
        },
        {
          "forAns": 2,
          "question": "Gently awaken the patient verbally ask their full name comparing it with the ID bracelet"
        },
        {
          "forAns": 3,
          "question": "Ask the attending nurse or the relative verifying with the ID bracelet"
        },
        {
          "forAns": 4,
          "question": "Verbally ask their full name, address and birthdate and countercheck with a valid ID"
        }
      ]
    },
    {
      "title": "Preferred site",
      "answers": ["Arterial Puncture", "Capillary Puncture", "Venipuncture"],
      "reference": "Methods of Collection",
      "questions": [
        {
          "forAns": 1,
          "question": "Radial artery"
        },
        {
          "forAns": 1,
          "question": "Brachial artery"
        },
        {
          "forAns": 1,
          "question": "Femoral artery, scalp artery, umbilical artery"
        },
        {
          "forAns": 2,
          "question": "Heel (lateral Plantar Area)"
        },
        {
          "forAns": 2,
          "question": "Finger"
        },
        {
          "forAns": 3,
          "question": "Antecubital Fossa (elbow pit)"
        },
        {
          "forAns": 3,
          "question": "Other arm and hand veins"
        }
      ],
      "notes": [
        {
          "forAns": "Finger",
          "note": [
            "Central palmar area of 3rd and 4th digit of non-dominant hand",
            "Used on adults or children (>1 y.o.)"
          ]
        },
        {
          "forAns": "Antecubital Fossa (elbow pit)",
          "note": [
            "Median cubital vein is preferred vein & the largest and the best anchored vein",
            "Cephalic vein - 2nd preffered vein",
            "Basilic vein - last choice"
          ]
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}
